Alcatraz. Only one man has ever broken out. Now five
million lives depend on two men breaking in.
The Rock is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Michael Bay.
When vengeful General Francis X.
Hummel seizes control of Alcatraz Island and threatens to launch missiles loaded with deadly chemical weapons into San Francisco, only a young FBI
chemical weapons expert and notorious Federal prisoner have the skills to penetrate the impregnable island fortress and take him down.
John Patrick Mason, played by Sean Connery.
Dr. Stanley Goodspeed, played by Nicolas Cage.
Brigadier General Francis X. Hummel, USMC, played by Ed Harris.
FBI Director James Womack, played by John Spencer.
Major Tom Baxter, played by David Morse.
Special Agent Ernest Paxton, played by William Forsythe.
The Rock is a 1996 American action thriller film directed by Michael Bay, produced by Don
Simpson and Jerry Bruckheimer, and written by David Weisberg, Douglas S.
Cook and Mark Rosner.
It stars Sean Connery, Nicolas Cage and Ed Harris, with supporting roles played by
Michael Biehn, William Forsythe, David Morse, and John Spencer.
Connery plays a former SAS captain and Cage, an FBI chemist, who must disarm missiles from a rogue group
of Force Recon Marines who have taken control of the former prison on Alcatraz Island.
The Rock was dedicated to the memory of Simpson, who
died five months before its release.
It was released by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution through
the Hollywood Pictures label on June 7, 1996.
It received generally positive reviews and was nominated
for Best Sound at the 69th Academy Awards.
It earned over $335 million at the box office on a production budget of $75
million, becoming the fourth highest-grossing film of 1996.
The Rock was remade in India in 2003 as Qayamat: City Under Threat.
The Rock was the basis for false descriptions of
the Iraqi chemical weapons program.
Britain's Secret Intelligence Service was led to believe Saddam Hussein was continuing to produce weapons of mass
destruction by a false agent who based his reports on The Rock, according to the Chilcot Inquiry.
The film explores themes of war veteran, san francisco,
california, fbi, mercenary, gas attack.
The tone is intense.